Boston School of Occupational Therapy (BSOT) Records UA032
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Audiovisual materials, 1920 -- 1995; 1930 -- 1995; UA032.009; 11.55 Linear Feet; 31 Digital Object(s)
  - Rehabilitation film strips, 1938 -- 1958; UA032.009.005
    - Bed Exercises II, 1938 -- 1945; UA032.009.143.00012 (Box data_value_missing_d73deb3131d2bf4c8c0afe43806b9f3e)
      - Bed Exercises II [2 of 3], 1938 -- 1945; UA032.009.143.00012.00002; Filmstrips, Inc.
      - Bed Exercises II [3 of 3], 1938 -- 1945; UA032.009.143.00012.00003; Filmstrips, Inc.
    - Bed Exercises III, 1938 -- 1945; UA032.009.143.00013 (Box 143)
      This reel is on an Eastman Safety Film 3. It contains the film, "Bed Exercises Part III: Sitting balance."
    - Bed Exercises IV, 1938 -- 1945; UA032.009.143.00014 (Box 143)
      This reel is on an Eastman Safety Film 3. It contains the film, "Bed Exercises Part IV: Moving into and out of bed."
    - Occupational Therapy Unlimited, 1958; UA032.009.143.00015; American Occupational Therapy Association (Box data_value_missing_d73deb3131d2bf4c8c0afe43806b9f3e)
      - Occupational Therapy Unlimited [1 of 2], 1958; UA032.009.143.00015.00001; American Occupational Therapy Association
        This film strip was produced by AOTA and contains information promoting occupational therapy as a profession.
      - Occupational Therapy Unlimited [2 of 2], 1958; UA032.009.143.00015.00002; American Occupational Therapy Association
    - O.T. Information Please, 1958; UA032.009.143.00016; American Occupational Therapy Association (Box 143)
      This filmstrip, produced by AOTA provides information about becoming an occupational therapist.
    - She Can Do It Herself (II), 1958; UA032.009.143.00017; New York University (Box 143)
      This filmstrip is printed on Eastman Safety Film 3. It was produced by New York University's Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation.
- Qualifying Papers, UA032.010; 1 Volumes
- Promotional materials and short-run publications, 1918 -- 2009; 1970 -- 2009; UA032.011; 0.75 Linear Feet
  This series contains brochures and other materials used to promote the Boston School of Occupational Therapy. It also contains short-run publications issued by the school, including the Student Handbook and the Alumni Association Newsletter (BSOTAANL).
  - Letterhead and envelope, 1970; UA032.011.111.00001 (Box UA032 Shared 2)
  - Brochure, folder and postcard, 1918 -- 2000; UA032.011.111.00002 (Box UA032 Shared 2)
    The folder contains BSOT's first promotional brochure from 1918 along with a brochure, folder, and postcard from 2000.
  - Departmental Post it notes, 2009; UA032.011.111.00003 (Box UA032 Shared 2)
  - BSOTAANL, 1936 -- 1940; UA032.011.111.00005 (Box UA032 Shared 2)
    This box contains the Boston School of Occupational Therapy Alumni Association Newsletter. Includes vol. 1 no. 1 from October 1936, vol. 3 no. 3 from March 1938, and vol. 4 no. 2 from August 1940.
  - BSOT Students' Handbook, 1959 -- 1960; UA032.011.111.00006 (Box UA032 Shared 2)
  - BSOT Student Handbook, 1967 -- 1968; UA032.011.111.00007 (Box UA032 Shared 2)
  - BSOT Student Handbook, 1978; UA032.011.111.00008 (Box UA032 Shared 2)
  - Brochures, 1938 -- 1940; UA032.011.111.00009 (Box UA032 Shared 2)
  - Brochures, 1978 -- 1979; UA032.011.111.00010 (Box UA032 Shared 2)
  - Module Manual, Fall, 1978 -- 1979; UA032.011.111.00011 (Box UA032 Shared 2)
  - Occupational Therapy promotional mug, 2000 -- 2009; UA032.011.111.00012 (Box Shared 49)
  - [Oh, Tease!], 1946; UA032.011.111.00013; Wright, Jean (Box Shared 49)
    This is book by Jean Wright was found in the reading room on March 29, 2012. It is a publication by the Boston School of Occupational Therapy and describes through illustrations and short captions the daily life of an occupational therapy student.
- Occupational therapy project samples and classroom materials, 1913 -- 1980; UA032.012; 0.25 Linear Feet; 1 Artifact(s)
  This series contains materials used and created in occupational therapy courses. The materials include workbooks, weaving samples, and a large workroom safety chart. It also includes two quilts, which might have been made by occupational therapy patients and used as an example in a classroom environment.
  - BSOT patches [3], 1950 -- 1970; UA032.012.136.00001 (Box 136)
    Dates are approximate. Additional patches can be found in UA032.008.133.00047.
  - Chip carving, 1936; UA032.012.136.00002 (Box 136)
    This folder contains a handbook by W.P. Thurber, published by Fellowcrafters, Inc. It is marked with the name, Codman, and might have belonged to Elizabeth Codman High, O.T.R.
  - Designs in leather with working patterns, 1913; UA032.012.136.00003 (Box 136)
  - Directions for making wampum hand-made sport belts, 1922; UA032.012.136.00004 (Box 136)
  - Net Weaving: A manual, 1926; UA032.012.136.00005 (Box 136)
  - A resource guide to habilitative techniques and aids for cerebral palsied persons of all ages., 1978; UA032.012.136.00006; High, Elizabeth Codman (Box 136)
  - Weaving samples and patterns, 1957 -- 1959; UA032.012.136.00007 (Box 136)
    Dates are approximate. These weaving samples were sent to Mary Barnes at BSOT by Jean Childs (BSOT '59) in January 2005.
  - Stanley safety chart, 1955 -- 1960; UA032.012.137.00001 (Box Large Map Case 2 Drawer 6)
    This folder contains a poster-sized cardboard chart with woodworking safety information. Each page of the chart is numbered, and some pages are missing. Included are no. 5, no. 6, no. 9, no. 10, no. 15 - 20, no. 25 - 32.
  - Tapestry, 1950 -- 1980; UA032.012.142.00001 (Box 142)
    Dates are approximate. This box contains two tapestries. Each tapestry has 24 squares, each with an embroidered image and initials. It is unknown whether the tapestry was created by occupational therapy patients or staff members. The tapestry is made of a thick burlap-like material and embroidered with colorful thread. Some squares depict images from nursery rhymes and fairy tales.
  - Tapestry, 1950 -- 1980; UA032.012.142.00002 (Box 142)
- Boston School of Occupational Therapy Album of Snapshots, 1954; UA032.013; 1.2 Linear Feet
  This series contains an album of snapshots from 1954. This book was found in the stacks on March 30, 2012. It was originally cataloged in the Classes Collection, UA039.
  - Boston School of Occupational Therapy Album of Snapshots, 1954; UA032.013.001.00001 (Box UA032 Shared 1)
- Master's theses, 1980 -- 2006; UA032.014; 15.6 Linear Feet
  This series is arranged alphabetically by last name of author.
  - Master's theses, Acc-Bor, 1983 -- 2004; UA032.014.144 (Box 144)
  - Master's theses, Bra-Coh, 1981 -- 2004; UA032.014.145 (Box 145)
  - Master's theses, Cos-Fin, 1986 -- 2005; UA032.014.146 (Box 146)
  - Master's theses, Fis-Gra, 1981 -- 2006; UA032.014.147 (Box 147)
  - Master's theses, Gre-Hum, 1982 -- 2005; UA032.014.148 (Box 148)
  - Master's theses, Iid-Law, 1982 -- 2006; UA032.014.149 (Box 149)
  - Master's theses, Lie-Mek, 1980 -- 2004; UA032.014.150 (Box 150)
  - Master's theses, Mer-O'Co, 1981 -- 2002; UA032.014.151 (Box 151)
  - Master's theses, Osb-Rob, 1983 -- 2004; UA032.014.152 (Box 152)
  - Master's theses, Rob-Sil, 1981 -- 2004; UA032.014.153 (Box 153)
  - Master's theses, Sin-Tse, 1981 -- 1998; UA032.014.154 (Box 154)
  - Master's theses, Tuc-Wil, 1981 -- 2005; UA032.014.155 (Box 155)
  - Master's theses, Wil-Zaz, 1982 -- 2000; UA032.014.156 (Box 156)
- 2019 accessions, 1923 -- 1963; UA032.015; 0.6 Linear Feet
  This series contains six books on early occupational therapy practices held by the Boston School of Occupational Therapy. Titles include "Syllabus for Training of Nurses in Occupational Therapy," "O.T. - A New Profession," "Prescribing Occupational Therapy," and various editions of "Occupational Therapy."
  This series is arranged in order of accession.
  This series is open for research.
  - Occupational therapy books, 1923 -- 1963; UA032.015.163; 0.6 Linear Feet (Box 163)
    This file contains six books on early occupational therapy practices held by the Boston School of Occupational Therapy. Titles include "Syllabus for Training of Nurses in Occupational Therapy," "O.T. - A New Profession," "Prescribing Occupational Therapy," and various editions of "Occupational Therapy."
    Immediate Source of Acquisition
    Transferred by Sharan Schwartzberg, 2019, accession UA-2019-073.
- Additional accessions, 1920 -- 2007; UA032.016; 3.6 Linear Feet
  - Student photographs, 1918 -- 1958; UA032-003 (Box 1)
    Photographs arranged alphabetically by last name.
  - Group therapy photographs and slides, 1920; UA032-001 (Box 2)
    Photographs and glass plate slides of group therapy exercises, circa 1920, published in Dr. Schwartzberg's "Functional Group Model."
  - Slides of students working at Walnut Street Center, circa 2005-2007; and BSOT 70th and 75th anniversary celebrations documentation, 1988 and 1993, UA032-002 (Box 3)
    20 years from date of creation.
    Walnut Street Center slides were commissioned between 2005-2007 for use in the Class OTS 219 group book, "Applying The functional Group Model" (Schwartzberg).
- 2021 accessions, circa 1945 -- 1959; UA032.004800; 0.2 Linear Feet 2 folders
  Gift of Barbara Fox Hochschild, 2021, accessions UA-2022-004 and UA-2022-025.
  This series is arranged in received order.
  This series contains two letters to Boston School of Occupational Therapy alumnae, as well as a course catalog and brochure. The letters address the relationship between Boston School of Occupational Therapy and Tufts University.
  - Letter and notice to Boston School of Occupational Therapy alumnae, 1945 May 14; 1959 December; UA032.004802 (Box 163, Folder 1)
  - Boston School of Occupational Therapy course catalog and brochure, circa 1950s --1957; UA032.004804 (Box 163, Folder 2)